what does a band 9 part 2 answer in
IELTS speaking look like let's find out
[Music]
hello this is Keith from English
speaking success and the website Keith
speaking Academy listen if you are
preparing for IELTS but you haven't seen
my website yet go and check it out
keithspeakingacademy.com it's full of
awesome resources that will help you
build your vocabulary and get you
speaking confidently in no time at all
today in today's video we're going to be
looking at a model answer for IELTS
speaking part two on the topic of
clothes and a full analysis of all the
language in there
actually this video comes from my online
course IELTS speaking success get a band
7 plus gold it's based on a very special
methodology I've created called the
speaking success system there are four
steps number one try to discover three
practice four build this video today
shows you the Discover stage number one
try is where you try and give an answer
number two discover is where I give you
a model answer and analyze all the
language that can help you build up the
language you need
step three is the practice where you
have more videos to practice all the
chunks from the model answer
juggling changing them using them so
that you're building up your confidence
as you use them step four at the end is
you build a much better answer
so you can find out more about the gold
course
um stick around to the end of the video
and I'll tell you a little bit more
about it for now let's get straight
stuck in to this model answer for part
two question about clothes and the full
analysis
okay so let's have a look at the part
two question describe a person who you
think wears unusual clothes
I've had my minute to prepare I've got
my notes ready let's do this
so I'm going to tell you about my
history teacher at University
um you know he was and still is a bit of
an eccentric
um especially when it comes to clothes
I would say his clothes are
unconventional to say the least many
students actually think he's just weird
to be honest he doesn't seem to care
what others think of his tasting clothes
I actually think he sees himself as
being quite fashionable
um so let me try to describe his rather
offbeat style to you
um for starters
he always wears odd color socks now this
must be on purpose because I can't see
how he could wear mismatching socks
every day if it were by accident
um next is trousers they always seem to
be too short and that's how you notice
his socks and more often than not he
wears braces rather than a belt
maybe it's because he's rather Stout and
chubby uh unfortunately it makes him
look a bit like a clown
finally he tends to spoil to sport
flamboyant shirts with complex patterns
and bright colors
but for me
um you know his clothes don't really
match I mean the colors don't go well
together if I'm honest
but he seems very comfortable and at
ease in what I would call very quirky
attire
of Lou
okay so there was a model answer for
part two let's have a look in detail at
the language I was using there okay so
first of all I'm going to tell you about
that's a great signpost and that's just
telling the examiner this is what I'm
going to talk about right you want to be
really clear don't be too fancy at the
start just go direct to it I'm going to
tell you about my history teacher you
know so you know is a filler
a lot of people think you shouldn't use
fillers in English and I disagree I
think you should use fillers in
moderation that means a little bit not
too much because it shows a lack of
control of the language but do you sum
because it's very very natural you know
he was and still is a bit of an
eccentric so an eccentric as we've said
is um a person who's very
uh unusual in their behavior or their
clothes very different maybe a bit like
charismatic but more just being
different from everybody else
and notice we often say a bit of an a
bit of a something and this just makes
it a bit softer you know especially in
British English we're quite soft with
our language and indirect right if I say
I'm a chef it sounds like I'm a bit
arrogant right I'm confident and and a
bit too arrogant if I say I'm a bit of a
chef I'm making it softer right that
it's not too arrogant it's a bit humble
so we often use this right a bit of an
eccentric
um especially when it comes to clothes I
would say his clothes are unconventional
we've mentioned which is um so
convention is tradition anything against
tradition the adjective is
unconventional
to say the least that's a lovely
connector right to say the least
um
to say the least just means what you've
just said is probably a lot worse
so when I come home right in the evening
and I say to my family oh I've had a
terrible day to say the least
it means it wasn't just terrible it was
really really really bad right it's a
lot worse than what I've said
um so it's normally used with something
negative to make it even more negative
right
um
you know I didn't enjoy that film to say
the least
means that not only did I not enjoy it I
really really hated it I didn't like it
at all
say the least my students think it's
just weird weird strange right weird
Okay
um
next to be honest again nice signpost
I'm gonna tell you something frankly
um he doesn't seem to care what others
think of his taste in clothes my tasting
clothes are the clothes you like
normally we think of taste as in eating
right but it can be in anything my taste
in music my tasting cars my tasting
clothes it's the things that you like
I actually think he sees himself as
being quite fashionable that means he
thinks he is fashionable I see myself as
being very British I see myself as being
a good listener
I see myself as being or he sees himself
as being quite fashionable right he
thinks nice language
next a nice signpost so let me try to
describe
okay it's a lovely signpost he's rather
offbeat style we've talked about offbeat
unusual
for starters another lovely signpost so
instead of saying first of all
in spoken English very natural for
starters right for starters he always
wears odd color socks odd colors means
the different colors right they're not
matching
okay good let's move on
this must be on purpose so we have two
phrases here on purpose and by accident
on purpose means deliberately you really
wanted to do it it wasn't a mistake by
accident means by mistake okay so if you
do something on purpose you want it to
happen if you do it by accident it was
just by by mistake you didn't mean for
it
um mismatching socks yeah that is the
same as Odd Socks they're mismatching
they're not matching they don't go well
together right hopefully my shirt and my
jumper match right it's a matching
outfit but sometimes I wear mismatching
shirts if the truth be known next
next another connector there
um his trousers seem to be too short and
more often than not he wears braces more
often than not just means usually most
times
in the morning more often than not I
have a cup of tea
not always but more often than not right
it's what it means usually
um it's true more often than not I have
a cup of tea
he wears braces braces are these things
that attach to your yes just like that
that attach to your trousers to hold up
your trousers
Stout and chubby are very similar words
in meaning um it's a polite way of
saying fat
fat is not very polite and we don't tend
to say that but you might say someone's
a bit chubby a little bit fat Stout is a
little fat but strong right quite big
and strong so those are quite almost
almost euphemistic words
unfortunately again connector it makes
him look a bit like a clown okay and
finally finally he tends to sport
flamboyant shirts we've looked at
flamboyant right something another good
word is exuberant
can you say that
exuberant eggs like fried eggs exuberant
exuberant it's an X but it's an egg
so flamboyant very bright
noticeable shirts
um for me just means
in my opinion or I think right for me I
like it
I think in my opinion I like it for me
his clothes don't really match
the colors don't go well together so go
well together is to match as we
mentioned the shirt and the jumper
um if I'm honest honestly speaking to be
honest
if the truth be told there's lots of
little phrases you can use there with
the same meaning and they're very nice
connectors
but
he seems comfortable and at ease is
relaxed in his quirky attire quirky as
we mentioned is unusual but in a
positive way
um quirky attire
attire nice formal word meaning clothes
that's it that's the language we've used
in the part two answer let's move on
what a nice answer I hope you liked that
listen if you want to find out more
about the gold online course you can
click on the link below when you join
the course there are three simple steps
to take number one you watch the course
videos and discover the language that
you need you can do this at your own
pace in your own time there are more
than a hundred model answers that will
help you build the vocabulary the
grammar the pronunciation that you need
to give better answers number two is to
practice speaking and building your
confidence with the speaking success
System videos and PDFs to work on number
three is to join the private Facebook
group watch the two live lessons a month
um and with that you can connect with
others and stay motive activated in your
study
this is the course that gets you
speaking confidently in weeks and loving
English for a lifetime
and there's more there is in fact a
discount 10 off for all YouTube viewers
just click on the link in the
description below and you will find that
if it's right for you go ahead
thank you so much for watching and I
well maybe I'll see you in the gold
course or at least in the next video
take care now bye
[Music]
foreign